Guide to the Marion Howe papers, 1879-1990.
Howe, Marion papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Marion Howe papers, 1879-1990.
6858
Howe, Marion
1.7 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Newspapers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, newspapers clippings and memoranda pertaining to Howe's work with the Cornell United Religious Work (CURW) and family.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell class of 1938.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, newspapers clippings and memoranda pertaining to Howe's work with the Cornell United Religious Work (CURW). Also includes family correspondence, largely relating to Delaware County, N.Y., especially letters between her father Harley Howe and her mother; photographs;, papers; and a sewing kit, baby bonnet, mittens and bib.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Howe, Marion; Howe family.; Howe, Harley Earl, 1882-; Cornell United Religious Work.; Cornell University--Alumni.; Cornell University.Class of 1938 Women.
Places:
Delaware County (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Marion Howe's Great-Grandfather's Account Book, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Marriage Certificate, 1879 (Folder O/S)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and his Mother, 1910 - 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and Eva Rich (Marion's Parents), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and Eva Rich, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and Eva Rich, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and Eva Rich, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence between Harley Howe and Eva Rich (Box 3)
- Notes concerning Correspondence between Marion's Parents (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence concerning Family History (includes photos), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence concerning Family History (includes photos) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mendenhalls and Macks - Photos and Family History (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Genealogical Research, 1967 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Marion Howe's 3rd Grade Class at East Hill School, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sewing Kit, Baby Bonnet, Mittens, Sachet and Lace Bib, 1918 (Box 4)
- Hooked Rug Made by Marion Howe, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Childhood Letterbook, Artwork (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ithaca High School and Jr. High School Memorabilia, 1931 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photos from Jr. High and Ithaca High School, 1924 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence to Marion Howe, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Artwork Done at Ithaca High School, 1931 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Ithaca High School Reunion Material, 1980s - 1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Marion Howe's CURW Position, 1959 - 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Marion Howe's Retirement, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Photographs of Marion Howe (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Biographical Material - Jack Lewis, 1957 - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, Talks, Articles - Jack Lewis, 1969 - 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Jack Lewis' Memorial Services, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence and Articles on Herman Yeung, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence and Articles about Barb and Doug Kneeland, 1997 - 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence and Articles concerning R.E. Loving, 1952 - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Articles and Memos concerning Sage Chapel, 1970 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Brian Robinson Files, 1985 - 2005 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence and Articles concerning Feynman's Films, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- McGuffey's Publications, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 32)
- CURW Staff Working in Anabel Taylor Hall, 1936 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Articles about the Chimes (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Cornell Daily Sun - special issue (laminated), October 25, 1952 (Folder O/S)
- CURW History, 1938 - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- CURW History, 1942 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- CURW History, 1955 -1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- CURW History, 1955 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Articles and Brochures - Anabel Taylor Hall (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publications Created at CURW (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CURW 50th Anniversary (includes photos), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Protestant Cooperative Ministry, 1960s - 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- One World Club; The Learning Web; Center for World Community at Cornell, 1962 -1963; 1974; 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Peace Service, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Obituaries and Programs from Memorial Services, 1969 - 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Talks, Papers, Programs, Articles on Religion, 1940s - 1960s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Talks, Papers, Programs, Articles on Religion, 1940s - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Clippings - Meditative Pieces, 1940s - 1960s (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Clippings - Meditative Pieces, 1960s - 1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Lectures, Talks, Broadcasts, 1936 - 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Sermons - Lutheran Series, 1964 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Sermons - Episcopal and Methodist Series, 1961 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- National Radio Pulpit, 1964 - 1965; 1978; 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Pamphlets Written by John Taylor (Box 2, Folder 18)
- The Protestant Hour Sermons, 1960s - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Photograph - Choir of the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca, 1924 (Folder O/S)
- Ithaca History, 1980s - 1990s (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Photo albums, clippings, documents, and correspondence (Box 5)
- Photos, genealogical information, correspondence, Eva Belle's year in Florence (Box 6)
- Mementos, notes, photos, cards, collections-humor and music (Box 7)
- A Sampler of the Life and Times of Marion L. Howe (Box 7)
- Correspondence, typed letter copies, CURW material, poems (Box 8)
- Calendars, clippings, cards, correspondence, and keys (Box 9)
- At a glance diaries, books, framed photos and paintings, blankets, stuffed bear, photo of stuffed bear (Box 10)
- Historical Society, clippings (Box 11)
- Clippings, photo album (Box 12)
- Paintings (Box 13)
- Eva Belle's Hair (Box 14)
- Two pieces of wedding cake, 1913-08-21 (Box 14)